TRAN CONG DANH

Binh Thanh, Ho Chi Minh City • 098 7777 972 • congdanhk07@gmail.com • 19/07/2000 <u>Linkedin • Github • My Portfolio</u>

SUMMARY

I'm a Front-end Developer with **3 years** of experience with React and Next.js, working with domain *e-commerce*, *cybersecurity* (*EDR*), and admin management. I'm familiar with backend development and eager to grow as a Full-stack Developer. Seeking opportunities to contribute to both front-end and back-end projects, delivering high-quality, well-rounded solutions

TECH STACK

- Frontend Technical Skills: Javascript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, React, NextJS, Material UI, Ant Design, Tailwind, SCSS/SASS.
- Backend Technical Skills: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Pocketbase.
- State Management: Redux Toolkit, Tanstack (React Query), v.v.
- · Others:
 - Understanding about SEO principles to optimize web applications for SERP.
 - Familiarity with Flutter, actively contributing to the development and support of mobile applications.
 - Basic experience in writing Unit Tests using Mocha, Chai.
- Languages: Vietnamese (Native), English

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer, DISION TECH LLC

Sep 2024 - Present

- Developed reusable and flexible UI components, ensuring efficient integration with APIs.
- Ensured website responsiveness across all devices and screen sizes.
- Troubleshooted complex issues and refactored code for optimal performance and maintainability.

Frontend Developer, SGMIO JSC

Apr 2022 - Sep 2024

- Create UI website of project with Javascript (ReactJS/NextJS), optimized components for better reusability.
- Maintained, reported, and optimized website performance and SEO, successfully achieving top rankings for products on SERP.
- Upgraded the website based on customer feedback.
- Ensured website responsiveness across all devices and screen sizes (mobile, tablet and desktop)

Frontend Developer, BESSFU Solution Technology

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022

- Developed and implemented user-friendly UI components based on Figma designs using Next.js, React.js, and MUI Material.
- Contributed to frontend development of an e-learning platform for the VUS English learning system, ensuring a smooth user experience and responsiveness.
- Optimized application performance and UI responsiveness to provide an engaging learning experience across devices.

PROJECT

Cyber Security - Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)

9/2024 - Now

- Developed an admin dashboard using Ant Design and Ant Design Charts, integrating data binding from S3 Minio.
- Implemented and managed playbook functionality with full CRUD operations.
- Integrated Wazuh APIs to develop alert features for endpoints, enhancing threat detection and response capabilities.
- Collaborated on building and enhancing other interfaces to improve user experience.

E-commerce Project: Japanese Fishing Rods • LINK

2023 - 2024

- Contributed to 40% of the UI development end-user.
- Implemented advanced search and filtering to enhance user experience, enabling keyword searches, category selection, and product filtering for efficient navigation.
- Optimized API management using Axios Interceptors, reducing redundant code and improving error handling, which contributed to a 10% boost in development productivity
- Handled user authentication processes and social login integration using Firebase.

LMS and Recruitment Project • LINK

2022 - 2023

- Enhanced performance page load by using SSG, SSR, and ISR in NextJS, reducing page load time by **15%** and participated in enhancing on-page SEO for the website.
- Led the development of the course module, including home course, detail, search, and filter pages with a focus on responsive design and usability.
- Optimized search and filtering functionality to enhance the user experience and improve performance.

Trello Clone Project (Personal)

9/2024 - Now

- Designed a modern and responsive UI with Material-UI (MUI), supporting dark/light mode and drag-and-drop functionality.
- Developed RESTful APIs for board management with MongoDB integration and implemented input validation using Joi.
- Implemented MVC architecture to structure the project.
- Configured Axios Interceptors to manage authentication workflows and handle errors across API requests.
- Managed application state using Redux Toolkit to ensure efficient state handling and predictable data flow.

CERTIFICATES

SOLID Principles: Software Architecture & Design • CERTIFICATE

Clean Code • CERTIFICATE

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

2018 - 2022

University of Resources and Environment

• TOIEC Certificate: 680